牢记”人格“
Remember the "Personality".
没有谋杀，好吗？
No murder, O.K?
让我们祈祷吧
Let's pray.
-爸爸？-祖哈尔？
- Dad? - Zuhal?
-你认识泰丰先生吗？-我当然认识
- Did you know Mr.Tayfun? - Of Course I did.
在坎布拉时就认识他
All the way from Kambura.
节哀
Sorry for your loss.
坚强起来孩子 没有人能逃过命运
Be brave son. You can't escape fate.
什么命运？他们把花匠炸死了
What fate? They blew up the flower man.
作为“狗杀手”粉丝俱乐部的创始人，我们正式欢迎你
As founders of the "Dog Killer" Fan Club we officially welcome you.
如果一周之内抓不到他，那就结束了
If you don't make an arrest within a week, it's over.
被塔亚尔强奸的女孩
The girl whom Tayyar raped...
她在跟我说话 看看她说的
she is talking to me. Look what she's saying.
救救我内芙拉
Help me Nevra.
直到现在，她一直在向我倾诉
Up until now, I have been her voice.
所有这些谋杀都是为了报仇
All these murders are for her revenge.
如果我们找到她，我们也找到这个凶手
If we find her we find this one too.
我们必须立即去坎布拉
We have to go to Kambura immediately.
女士们，任何遭受过性虐待或强奸的人……
Ladies, anyone who was raped or sexually abused...
请打这个电话
please call this number.
“他们把女人们聚集起来”是什么意思？
What do you mean by "they gathered the women"?
她试图找到被塔亚尔强奸的女孩
She is trying to find the girl who was raped by Tayyar.
好吧，你待命 我要想一想
O.K, just stand by. I'll think of something.
他们检查了烧毁的房子
They checked out the burned house.
马上找一台推土机
Find a bulldozer immediately.
把房子拆掉
And knock it down.
-一个陌生号码 -快接
- I don't recognize the number. - Go on, answer it.
喂？
Hello?
从头说起 把一切都告诉我
Just tell me everything from the beginning.
那是很平常的一天 我刚在杂货店买完东西
It was an ordinary day. I had just finished my grocery shopping.
我离开商店时，塔亚尔突然出现
As I left the shop Tayyar appeared out of nowhere.
他抓住了我……
He grabbed me and...
然后，在树林里……
you know, in the woods.
她记得一切
She remembers everything.
有什么需要就打给我
Just call me if you need anything.
非常感谢 你不必在这里等的
Thank you very much. You don't need to hang around.
菲鲁兹
Firuz...
你知道得越少 晚上睡得越香
the less you know, the better you can sleep at night.
那样的话你就不会打电话给我了
Then you won't have to call me...
或者说“别管我”
or say "leave me alone".
你认为内芙拉被说服了吗？
Do you think Nevra was convinced?
绝对的
Absolutely.
我讲故事的技巧很好，她都快要哭了
She was about to start crying, thanks to my story-telling skill.
顺便说一句，我跟塞米尔谈过 他说我的钱在你这里
By the way, I talked to Cemil. He said you have the rest of my money.
是的，在这
Yes, that's right.
-妈的！-什么？
- S..it! - What is it?
你还说服了呢
So much for been convinced.
她在跟着我们
She is following us.
-在哪里？-不要转身
- Where? - Don't turn around.
我们现在要做什么？
What are we going to do now?
妈的！
S..it!
我现在该怎么办？
What am I going to do now?
现在怎么办？
What now?
想想你的家在哪里？
Think. Where is your home?
想，想，想
Think, think, think.
你的房子在哪里？
Where is your house?
不，这行不通
No, it's not going to work.
费扎夫人！
Mrs Feza!
我们走吧
Let's go.
来吧，起来吧 我们走
Come on, get up. Let's go.
站起来，我不知道该去哪里，但我们该走了
Get up. I don't know where but we should go.
干得好
Here you go.
我的包……
My bag...
还有别的吗？
anything else?
好的，走这边 是的
O.K, this way Mrs Feza. Here you go.
她还在跟着你吗？
Is she still following you?
不要停下 菲鲁兹
Keep going Firuz.
在我想到解决方案之前不要下车 明白吗？
Don't get out the car until I think of something, O.K?
费扎夫人！
Mrs Feza!
我读过数千本小说，所以我决定自己写一个
I've read thousands of novels and I decided to write one myself.
但是你们两个都搞砸了
And you two f..cked it up.
-现在听我说 -我在听 塞米尔先生
-Listen to me now. -I am listening Mr.Cemil.
-你能听到我说话吗？耶利兹 -是的，我可以
- Can you hear me Yeliz? - Yes, I can.
我打了几个电话 我们将改变这个故事
I made some calls. We'll change the story a little.
我要说的是，把它记在脑子里
What I'm about to say, get it into your heads.
哪怕犯一个小错误 你就完了
Smallest mistake, you're done with.
喂？
Hello?
你是认真的吗？
Are you serious?
耶利兹与菲鲁兹见面？一定有什么误会吧
Yeliz met with Firuz? There must be a mistake.
没有误会 他们就在我前面
No mistake. They are right ahead of me.
很明显，他们彼此认识 他现在正开车带她去什么地方
It is obvious that they know each other. He is driving her somewhere.
好 等一下 冷静一下
O.K. Hang on a minute. Just calm down.
你是说耶利兹昨晚在跟你扯淡吗？
Do you mean Yeliz was bulls... tting you last night?
现在，她和菲鲁兹在一起，对吗？
And now, she is with Firuz, right?
是的，就是这样
Yes, that's exactly so.
我必须和菲鲁兹谈谈这到底是怎么回事
I have to talk to Firuz to find out what's been happening.
先挂了
Just hang up.
现在别打给他 塞法 我必须看看他们要去哪里
Don't call him now Sefer. I have to see where they are headed.
听我说 没有人比我更了解菲鲁兹
Listen to me. No one knows Firuz better than I do.
如果有什么不愉快的事情，他也不会接
If there is something iffy going on, either he won't answer...
也不会跟我说废话
or give me a lot of crap.
我必须打电话给菲鲁兹找出答案
I have to call Firuz to find out.
-等一下-什么？
- Hang on a minute. - What?
你会告诉他我一直在跟着他吗？
Are you going to tell him that I've been following him?
以我对菲鲁兹的了解，他已经知道了自己在被跟踪
If I know Firuz well enough, he already figured out that he's being followed.
不，也不在这里
No, it is not here either.
我记下了一切
I made a note of everything.
甚至记录了不喜欢电视机，但没有地址
Even, chucking the TV set out. But no address.
我好笨
I am so stupid.
可怜的阿加
Poor Agah.
也不在钱包里
Not in the wallet either.
但这应该在汽车的日志上
But it should be on the car's log book.
是的，应该在日志上
Yes, it should be on the log book.
冷静下来 阿加
Calm down Agah.
深呼吸
Take a deep breath.
谢谢
Thank you.
深呼吸
Take a deep breath.
费扎夫人，我不记得我住在哪里了
Mrs. Feza, I don't remember where I live.
我不记得我的家了
I don't remember my home.
这到底是怎么回事？
What the hell is going on?
继续做你一直在做的事
Keep doing whatever you've been doing.
什么？
Excuse me?
继续跟着我 我叫了塞法 他在路上
Keep following me. I called Sefa. He is on his way.
我们必须坐下来谈谈
We have to sit down and talk.
应该都在这里
Everything should be here.
我把所有笔记都记在这个黑本子里
I make a note of everything in this black book.
上面写着：“ 8号公寓的密码组合是1682”
It says here "Combination for the Flat No 8 is 1682".
但是什么是8号公寓？
But what is Flat No:8?
到底在哪里？我怎么知道？
Where the hell is it? How the hell do I know?
我为什么不写下地址而写了密码组合呢？
Why didn't I write down the address instead of the combination?
我真是个白痴！
Such an idiot!
很不幸，这就是我们现在的情况
Unfortunately, this is the situation we are in right now.
我不记得了
I don't remember.
一定是有原因的
There must be a reason why I forgot.
我带你去海边
I'll take you to seaside.
我可以为你演奏弗拉门戈舞
I can play flamenco for you.
-奥莱！-是的，奥莱！
- Olé! - Yes, sure, Olé.
还记得你问我这个想法是怎么产生的吗？
Remember when you asked me how the idea came up?
当你说为什么其他人要决定别人的生死时？
When you said why should others decide who is to be killed?
你知道为什么吗？
Do you know why?
因为他们一直是决定的人
Because they've always been the ones to decide.
过来
Come over here.
杰罗姆在1872年画了这幅画
Gerome painted this in 1872.
那些人在做什么？
What are those people doing?
那幅画叫做“ Pollice Verso”
That's what the painting is called. "Pollice Verso".
意思是“拇指向下”
It means "thumbs down".
那是给谁画的？
And who is it for?
给角斗士
For the gladiator.
为什么？所以他可以杀了这个人
Why? So he can kill this man.
实际上，在古罗马尚不清楚哪一个意味着“死亡”
Actually, it is not clear which one means "death" in ancient Rome.
这个或这个
This, or this.
但是杰罗姆认为这是一个合适的选择
But Gerome thought this was the fitting one.
如果这样做，角斗士就会杀人
If you do this, the gladiator will kill.
竞技场中将会有人死亡
And there would be death in the Arena.
如果这样，你可以挽救人的性命
If you do this you save the man's life.
但是一个人这样做还不够 决定必须是一致的
But one is not enough. The decision has to be unanimous.
我的意思是，生或死必须共同决定
What I mean is, who will die or live has to be decided unanimously.
一致的决定总是被认为是合法的
Unanimous decisions are always deemed legitimate.
它会带走内疚的良心
It will take the guilty conscience away.
归根结底，这是煽动谋杀
At the end of the day, you are inciting to a murder.
这是犯罪
It is a crime.
但是这样，每个人都可以互相指责
But this way, everybody can point the finger at each other.
罪行就消失了
And the crime disappears.
这幅画告诉我们的是
What this painting tells us that...
如果你想犯罪而不会受到指责
if you want to commit a crime and not get blamed...
你所要做的就是在你周围建立一个群体
all you have to do is to build a crowd around you.
如果你在足够多的群体中进行犯罪，就不再是犯罪
It is no longer a crime, if you commit it with a large enough crowd.
而且……
And...
这些会让你想到什么吗？
do these remind you anything?
嗯……
Well...
你将视频上传到YouTube
you upload a video on YouTube.
发生的这些事情是由你甚至不认识的人来判断
What happens is that it is judged by people you don't even know.
喜欢
Like...
不喜欢
and dislike.
生
Life...
或死
or death.
如你所见，两千多年来，一切都没有改变 苏薇达
As you can see, nothing has changed in 2 thousand years Süveyda.
唯一的区别是你不能再做拇指向上或向下的动作
Only difference is that you can't do this anymore.
你必须点击图标
You have to click on the icons.
我看到画的时候就想到了
I thought of it when I saw the painting.
我们有角斗士，所以让人群决定谁会死
We have the gladiator, so let the crowd decide who'll die.
-听说了吗？-什么？
- Did you hear it? - What?
被杀的三个人？
The three man who were killed?
额头刻有“个人”的三人？
The ones with the word "personal" carved on their forehead?
他们在我们网站的名单上
They were on the list in our website.
-真的吗？-为什么不自己看一下？
- Are you serious? - Why don't you check it out?
打开电脑 苏薇达
Switch on the computer Süveyda.
我在学校知道的 他们刚刚告诉我
I found out at school. They just told me.
其中一个人是经营食品亭还是什么的
One of them was running a food kiosk or something.
他说：“他们勒索我的钱，我希望“狗杀手”能把他们都杀死”
He says "they are extorting money from me. I hope the "Dog Killer" kill them all".
就在谋杀的前一天 他们在网站上公布了姓名
They issued the names too Only a day before the murders.
人们疯狂起来了 每个人都在列表上输入名字
And people went wild. Everybody is loading names on the list.
你知道这意味着什么吗？
You know what this means don't you?
“狗杀手”正在关注我们的网站
"Dog Killer" is following our website.
好吧，那你在做什么？你怎么认识这个女人？
Alright then. What were you doing there? How do you know this woman?
别着急 等塞法来了再说
No rush. There is a time for everything. Wait till Sefa gets here.
他来了
Here he is.
你以为你在做什么？
What the hell do you think you're doing?
这样说吧 脏活必须由我来做
Put it this way, I have to do the s... itty work...
因为你一点用都没有
because you have been so f..cking useless.
-你在说什么？-谋杀案每天都在发生
- What are you talking about? - Murders are piling up every day.
你们的大脑被坎布拉弄得一团糟
And your brains are messed up with Kambura.
我们一点头绪都没有
We are not getting anywhere.
安卡拉的人生气了 我必须要做点什么
They are going mad in Ankara. And I have to take all the s... it.
还记得昨天去医院吗？
Remember coming to the hospital yesterday?
你离开后他们就来找我
They called me straight after you left.
-谁是“他们”？-安卡拉高层人士
- Who are "they"? - Ones at the top in Ankara.
他们说“那边有点问题 跟进一下”
They said "there is something iffy going on over there. Dig into it".
我说“你是要我调查我的同事吗？”
I said "you want me to investigate my partners"?
他们说“正是”
They said "exactly".
长官好
Yes sir.
-老大知道吗？-他们可能和他说了
- Does boss know about it? - They probably told him.
反正我也要去和他谈谈
I'll go and talk to him anyway.
我已经担任主管多年了，我不会监视我的团队
I have been a superintendent for years. I am not going to spy on my team.
他们告诉托尔加检察官，给了他一周的时间
They told Chief Tolga, gave him a week.
如果他解决不了，他们会让他滚蛋
If he can't solve it they'll show him the door.
是的，长官，我知道
Yes sir, I understand sir.
是的，你已经告诉我了
Yes, you've told me sir.
但我认为这是不必要的
But I think it is unnecessary.
不是
No.
因为我相信我的团队 长官
Because I trust my team sir.
好
O.K.
我明白
I understand.
那是什么？他们怀疑我们吗？
So, what is it? Do they suspect us?
谢谢
Thanks.
不要装傻了 Sefa
Don't pretend that you don't already know Sefa.
他们是在欺骗我们
They are just pulling the wool over eyes.
当案情恶化时，他们想要证明自己的行为是正确的
They will want to justify their action when the case blows bigger...
在几天之内
in couple of days.
他们会说：“我们调查了警察”
They'll say "we investigated the cops."
每个人都在努力拯救自己
Everybody is trying to save their own a..ss.
都是为了保住官服
It is all about saving your skin.
就是这样
That's what it is.
没什么比海边更好的了
Nothing beats the seaside.
没有了
Nothing can beat it.
自从我上一次在这里放风筝已经过去50年了
It must've been 50 years since I last flew a kite.
至少50年
50 years at least.
我必须奔跑才能飞起来 但是我怎么跑？
I have to run to fly it. But how can I run?
我很快就回来 等我一下
I'll be back in a minute. Wait here.
让我问你一件事？
Let me ask you something?
你是如何知道的？
How did you figure it out?
我的意思是，你如何得知我要去见那个女人？
I mean, how did you figure out that I was going to meet the woman?
我不知道你们会见面
I didn't figure out that you were going to meet.
我只知道她在撒谎
I only figured out that she was lying.
但是她告诉我的一切都是有道理的
But everything she told me made sense.
是的，一切都说得通
That's right, it all made sense.
除了一件事
Except one thing.
坎布拉没有任何一个男人会娶一个不是处女的老婆
No man in Kambura would marry a non-virgin.
无论是否爱她
It doesn't matter how much he loves her.
这违反了坎布拉的习俗
It is against Kambura's customs.
这就是为什么这个女人既没有被强奸过也没有结过婚
That's why, the woman in question either never got raped nor she is married.
但是因为我知道她已经结婚了，所以我决定跟随她……
But since we knew she was married, I decided to follow her...
查清楚她要去哪里，谁在强迫她说谎
to find out where she was going and who was forcing her to lie.
那时候我就看到了你
That's when you came into the scene.
你做得很好
You're doing good.
可能不是很好
May be not so good.
但是你会成功的
But you'll do it.
-我做不到-你可以的
- I can't do it. - You can do it.
我告诉你，让我们再尝试10次，
I'll tell you what, let's try 10 more times and...
如果还是不行，我们就停下
we'll quit if it doesn't work out.
继续 这是第一次 我们从第一次开始
Go on. This is the first. We start with the first one.
费扎夫人
Mrs. Feza.
来吧
Come on.
没关系
It's O.K.
我们来尝试第二次
Let's go for the second.
来吧孩子
Come on son.
做得好
Well done.
不 这边
No, this way.
快点
Faster.
第三次
Three.
第四次
For the forth time.
撒谎？我为什么要骗你
Lie? Why should I lie to you?
如果你不相信我 那你去问问我的丈夫
If you don't believe me ask my husband.
问他我结婚时是不是处女
Ask him if I was virgin when we got married.
好了 内芙拉
It's O.K Nevra.
够了，我们会送你去你想去的地方
That's enough. We'll drop you off wherever you want to go.
你算什么女人 让我谈论这些事情？
What sort of a woman are you, making me talk about such things?
你怎么能对自己的同类做这种事情？你没有感情吗？
How can you do this to your own kind? Have you got no feelings?
你妈妈过去曾对你说过什么？
What did your mum used to say to you Yeliz?
那是什么意思？跟这有什么关系？
What do you mean? What's that got to do with anything?
你妈妈小时候对你说了什么？
What did your mum used to say to you when you were little?
她怎么威胁你？
How was she threatening you?
她是不是在说“你想成为妓女”吗？
Wasn't she saying "do you want to become a whore"?
“你最终会变成妓女”
"You'll end up becoming a whore".
她没说过吗？
Isn't that what she was saying?
那和这有什么关系？
What's that got to do with anything?
她就是这么说的，不是吗？
That's what she used say, wasn't it?
你知道为什么吗？因为你的妈妈明确的知道坎布拉是什么样子
Do you know why? Because your mum knew exactly what Kambura was like.
你也知道
You know too.
如果你想知道到底是谁的错，那就是坎布拉本身
If you are looking for a wrong doing, it is the Kambura itself.
先生你看，飞起来了
Look mister, it is flying.
甚至可能是这样……
It may even be so that...
你说的是真相
you're telling the truth Yeliz.
你真的被强奸了
You really have been raped.
是的，为什么不是？
Yes, why not?
昨天你在谈论细节的时候
Yesterday you were talking about everything in detail.
你回避了强奸的问题，为什么？
But you avoided the subject of rape. Why?
因为你做不到
Because you couldn't do it.
你有胆量骗我们
You had the guts to lie to us.
但是你从来没有勇气告诉你发生了什么
But you never had the courage to tell what happened to you.
你是真的被强奸了 耶利兹
You really have been raped Yeliz.
费扎夫人 飞起来了
Mrs Feza, it is flying.
我们终于做到了
We finally did it. It's flying.
费扎夫人！
Mrs Feza!
飞起来了
It's flying.
然后，你嫁给了强奸你的男人
And then, you married the man who raped you.
为什么？因为这个叫做坎布拉的地方给了你另一种选择
Why? Because the place called Kambura never left you with another choice.
就是这样，不是吗？
That's what happened, isn't it?
来，说吧 那不是真相吗？
Come on, say it. Isn't that what happened?
够了 内芙拉 别说了
That's enough Nevra. Leave the girl alone.
因为你无话可说
Because you've got nothing to say.
这意味着塔亚尔没有对你做过任何事情
It means that it's not Tayyar who did this to you.
他可能对别人做了，但不是对你
He might've done it to somebody else, but not to you.
但是你为什么说谎，把责任推给他？
But why are you lying, blaming him?
这就是你想要相信的吗?
Is that what you want to believe?
你认为自己是在欺骗谁？骗自己还是骗我们？
Who do you think you're fooling? Yourself or us?
你认为如果你把矛头指向塔亚尔，你的丈夫会逃脱惩罚吗?
Do you think your husband will get away with it if you point the finger at Tayyar?
我告诉你，你可以责怪世界上所有的男人……
I'll tell you what, you can blame all the men in the world...
但这并不能给你丈夫脱罪
but it doesn't clear off your husband.
我要去坎布拉 你来吗？
I am off to Kambura. Are you coming?
当然
Sure I am.
你也可以跟踪我们，因为你的工作就是监视我们
You can tag along too, since your job is to spy on us.
坎布拉见
Don't bother, we'll meet you there.
卡住了
It got stuck.
风筝被卡住了
The kite got stuck.
费扎夫人
Mrs Feza...
风筝
the kite...
费扎夫人
Mrs Feza!
风筝被卡住了
The kite got stuck.
可怜的阿加
Poor Agah.
你就要变成这样了
That's exactly what you'll become.
无所谓了
Never mind.
-你好阿提斯 -内芙拉，你在哪里？
- Hello Ate?. - Nevra, where are you?
我要去坎布拉
I am off to Kambura.
我正想让你也一起来呢
I was about to ask you to come to Kambura.
你在那里吗？
Is that where you are?
我第一次来伊斯坦布尔时发现了这个地方
I discovered this place when I first came to Istanbul.
那时我还是个学生
When I was a student.
就成为了这里的常客
I became a regular customer.
你喜欢吗？
Do you like it? Nice isn't it?
是的，很好，但是……
Yes, it is nice but...
这些人是干嘛的？
how about the guys?
他们在工作
They are on duty.
我也不喜欢成群结队
I don't like going around in herds either.
但是我被一个精神病缠住了，你看到了
But I am being stalked by a psychopath. You saw it.
你甚至比我看的更清楚
You even saw him better than me.
我应该做些什么？
What am I supposed to do?
改变习惯，直到他们逮捕了那个凶手
Change your routine until they arrest the man.
在那个男人开始搅乱我的生活之前，我一直都是这样
I had a routine until that man began messing with my life.
如果你问天堂是什么样的……
If you ask me what paradise is like...
我会说“是一个每天都一样的地方”
I'd say "it is a place where every day is the same".
一切都没有改变，包括我
Where nothing changes, including me...
一切顺利的地方
a place where everything runs smooth.
事实上，我建了这样一个地方并住在那里
As a matter of fact, I built such a place and lived there.
现在，有一个魔鬼在我的天堂
Now, there is a devil in my paradise.
你要我因为他而关闭我的天堂吗？
Do you want me to close down my paradise because of him?
现在，那里也有天使
And now, there is an angel there too.
在这种情况下
In this case...
塞米尔先生
Mr Cemil...
恶魔和天使同时闯入你的天堂
is it coincidence that the devil and the angel made their way into your...
难道是巧合吗？
paradise simultaneously?
是受邀而来？
have invaded?
还是命运？
Or was it fate?
我不太了解，但我必须把门打开
I don't know that much but I must've left the door open...
让他们都进来
allowing both the devil and the angel in.
不是这里
This is not the place.
我为什么来这里？
Why did I come here?
这个地方……
This is the place...
曾经住着我的老朋友纳齐夫
where an old friend used to live. His name is Nazif.
现在他自称“纳兹”
Now he calls himself "Naz".
没关系，我认为没关系
It's O.K I suppose. No harm in it.
我曾经在这里做过一些事
I once did something here.
他们说，凶手总是回到谋杀现场
They say the killer always returns to the scene of murder.
我也是
So did I.
我本该忘记的这个的
I was supposed to forget about it.
等一下，你女儿不在这里 对吧？
Wait a minute, your daughter is not here, is she?
我们可以去你家了 那里没有监控
We can go to your place. There are no cameras there.
房子是空的
The house is empty.
我可以为你演奏弗拉门戈舞
I can play flamenco for you.
奥莱！
Olé!
是的，奥莱
Yes, sure. Olé.
-你怎么知道的？-我想看看这个地方
- How did you find out? - I wanted to see the place.
一名男子上吊自杀，给镇子造成破坏
A man hung himself, causing havoc in the town.
我来看一看 然后就这样了
I came to check it out. And this is the situation.
如你所见，房子已经不复存在了
As you can see, the place has gone back in time.
他们什么也没剩下 用泥土完全掩埋了
There is nothing left. They covered it with earth, buried it completely.
我想知道是谁做的？
I wonder who did it?
那个我也知道了
I found out that too.
哈夫兰控股
Havran Holding.
他们两年前从农民手里买了这块土地
They bought the land from a farmer two years ago.
哈夫兰控股
Havran Holding.
他们有基金会，为孩子们提供奖学金
They have foundations, granting scholarship to children.
塞米尔·哈夫兰是首席执行官
Cemil Havran is the CEO.
他来自坎布拉
And he is from Kambura.
塞米尔
Cemil.
是的，我们将在那里建立医院。请问你叫什么名字？
Yes, we will build a hospital there. What is your name please?
内芙拉·埃尔玛斯
Nevra Elmas.
内斯林夫人的女儿
Mrs Nesrin's daughter.
我当然认识她
Of course I know her.
怎么认识的？当然是在坎布拉认识的
Where from? Kambura of course.
你还有其他疑问吗？
Do you have any more questions Miss Nevra?
是的，我有
Yes, I have.
过了这么多年 是什么原因使你拆掉了这房子？
What made you knock this building down after all these years?
-尤其是在……-在那场悲剧之后
-Especially right after... -Yes. Right after a sad incident.
我非常了解乌福克
And I knew Ufuk very well.
我很伤心
Sad.
愿他安息
May he rest in peace.
听着，内芙拉小姐，你也可以被称为坎布拉人
Look Miss Nevra, you can be called a native of Kambura.
坎布拉对我来说是重要的地方
Kambura is a significant place for me.
一条生命在那里结束了
A life has vanished there.
我们决定做一些事情，为其他生命的繁荣铺平道路
We decided to do something that would pave way for other lives to flourish.
你理解吗？
Do you understand?
这就是为什么我们决定建一家医院
That's why we decided to build a hospital.
我告诉你我们能做什么
I tell you what we can do...
找个时间见一面
make an appointment with me...
我们坐下来聊天愉快，喝杯咖啡
we sit down and a have nice chat over a nice cup of coffee.
顺便说一句，这是我的私人电话
By the way, this is my private number.
你是警察
You're with the police force.
因此，你毫无疑问能够获得我的电话号码
Therefore you had no problem of obtaining my number.
但是，不要再给我打电话这个号码
But, don't call me on this number again.
实际上，最好忘记这个号码
In fact, it is better if you forget this number.
最好将其从联系人列表中删除
It is best if you delete it from your contacts list.
但如果你给我造成了太多麻烦，我会与你的老板联系
But if it's too much trouble for you, I get in touch with your bosses...
他们可以帮你
and they can do it for you.
好吗？
Is it O.K?
代我向你母亲致意
Give my regards to your mother.
愚蠢的女孩
Stupid girl.
她费了很大劲才找到你的电话号码
She's gone into all that trouble to find your number...
就为了问这事情
to talk about this.
我们不要说“愚蠢”
Let's not say "stupid"...
可以说“热情”
let's say "enthusiastic".
年轻
Young.
从来没碰过壁
Never ran into a wall.
他们又把它弄坏了
They broke it again.
他们把门锁弄坏了 费扎夫人
They broke the lock Mrs Feza.
现在可以了
It is O.K now.
锁匠曾说过他们会跟随你的行动
The locksmith had said that they follow your moves.
当他们知道到房子里面没人的时候，他们会闯进来
They broke in when they realized that the house was empty.
是不是？
Isn't that right?
我查过了没什么损害 我不认为他们拿走了任何东西
I checked the place. Not much damage. I don't think they took anything.
但除此之外卧室有点凌乱……！
The bedroom is a little messy. But apart from that...!
那里应该有一条鱼 我想知道它是否还活着
There is supposed to be a fish there. I wonder if it's still alive.
它有名字吗？
Did it have a name?
鱼的名字叫菲扎太太吗？
Did the fish have a name Mrs Feza?
你给它起了什么名字？
What did you name it?
如果是我，我怎么称呼它？
What would I name it if it was me?
阿加？
Agah?
是？
Yes?
你杀了穆罕默德
You killed Mehmet.
他们说费扎夫人被绑架了
They say Mrs Feza was kidnapped.
我已经报警了 警察在找她
I reported it to the police. They are looking for her.
我告诉警察她丈夫发生了什么
I told them what happened to her husband.
他们说这可能与之无关
They say it probably has nothing to do with it.
他们什么都不知道 警察真没用
They know nothing. Cops are useless.
终于接电话了！从早上以来我一直试图联系你
Finally! I have been trying to get hold of you since morning.
我知道爸爸 很抱歉 今天很忙
I know dad. I am sorry. It's been such a hectic day.
我还是很忙 但如果有紧急情况你可以和我谈谈
I am still busy. But you can talk to me if it's emergency.
你还记得法官穆罕默德·尤尔吉尔吗？
Do you remember the judge, Mehmet Yurtgil?
他的妻子费扎住在这里 有人绑架了她
His wife Feza was staying here. They kidnapped her.
绑架了？什么时候？
Kidnapped? Who? When?
今天早上，在公园散步时
This morning, during the stroll in the park.
他们说她迷路了 但是我确定她是被绑架了
They say she got lost. But I am sure she was kidnapped...
被杀她丈夫的杀手
by her husband's killer.
他们向警察报告了，但是警察没有做任何事情
They reported it to the police. But the police is not doing anything.
他为什么要绑架她？她病得很重。
Why would they kidnap her? She was very ill.
我认为他绑架她是为了让她闭嘴
I think they kidnap her to stop her telling the story.
她可能会透露自己目睹的事情
She may reveal what she witnessed to.
你不能相信人类的大脑 你永远不知道它是如何运作的
You can't trust human brain. You can never know how it works.
如果你是凶手，你会冒险吗？
Would you take the risk if you were the murderer?
而且，费扎夫人最近开始说话了
Moreover, Mrs Feza had begun to talk recently.
她在说什么
What was she saying?
她是在读诗吗？
She was reading poems?
我懂了
I see.
去太空？
To the space?
我知道了，爸爸，我会处理的
I've got it, dad. I'll take care of it.
不用担心，我会处理的
Don't worry, I'll take care of it.
这是怎么回事？谁绑架了谁？
What's going on? Who kidnapped who?
费扎·尤尔吉尔，穆罕默德·尤尔吉尔的妻子
Feza Yurtgil, Mehmet Yurtgil's wife.
她患有阿尔茨海默氏病
She suffers from Alzheimer's Disease.
她在公园里失踪了
She's gone missing in the park.
另外，纳兹姆·希克梅特去了太空，但警方对此一无所知
By the way, Naz?m Hikmet travelled to space but police didn't know about it.
我们走吧
Let's go.
但是，我们不接受媒体采访
Unfortunately, we are closed to the press.
反正他会查出来的
He will find out anyway.
我们中间的告密者会告诉他一切
The anonymous tipper among us will tell him everything.
现在或以后，有什么区别？
Now or later, what is the difference?
你们不是应该感到羞耻的人
You are not the ones who should be ashamed.
那些将你们视为商品的人
The ones who see you as an item to be bought and sold...
他们才是应该感到羞耻的人
they are the ones who should be ashamed.
他们教了我们什么？
What did they teach us?
完成相反的
Complete the opposite.
你被强奸了，因为你摇了摇尾巴
You've got raped because you've wagged your tail.
你在街上受到骚扰，因为你的身体暴露得太多了
You got harassed on the street because you revealed your body too much.
那么多年轻女孩在坎布拉弯着腰走路……
So many young girls walking bent-over in Kambura...
为了向男人们隐藏她们的胸部
to hide their breasts from men.
你知道吗？
Are you aware of it?
儿童背上的驼??峰
The hump on children's back...
是我们的错
is our fault.
梅布鲁雷以前用开襟衫靠在我的背上进行测量。
Mebrule used to hold the cardigan against my back to measure it.
她去世后我接手了
I am taking over from she left off.
我希望她还在，那样我可以为她编织一些东西
I wish she was here so I could knit something for her.
但是这里太黑了
But it is too dark to see in here.
抱歉，费扎太太 我们被困在黑暗中
I am sorry Mrs Feza. We are left in the dark.
但是我们必须这样做，以防其他人看到里面发生了什么
But we had to do it to stop others seeing what's going on inside.
门不能锁
The door can't be locked.
甚至都关不上，更不用说锁门了
You can't even shut it properly, let alone locking it.
穆尼尔曾经也很讨厌门
Mr Münir used to hate the doors too.
穆尼尔先生，我的猫
Mr Münir, my cat.
他讨厌关门
He hated closed doors.
他曾经用爪子敲它，要我打开它
He used to tap it with his paw, asking me to open it.
但是他在最后的日子非常疲惫
But he was so exhausted in his final days.
他无法起床
He was unable get up.
他甚至无法起床 无法要水喝
He was unable to get up to even ask for water.
我从来没有意识到
And I never realized.
如此有趣
So intriguing.
这个
This...
看
look.
文档分类指南
Guide to Documentation Sorting.
我也有这本书
I have this book too.
这个人
This man.
他的名字叫塔亚尔·凯马克
His name is Tayyar Kaymak.
他在10到15年前在坎布拉强奸了一个女孩
He raped a girl in Kambura sometime between 10 and 15 years ago.
我们不知道她当时多大
We don't know how old she was at the time.
但是她现在是成年女性
But she is an adult woman now.
女士们，我在找这个女人
Ladies, I am looking for this woman.
如果你对这个女人有任何线索，请挺身而出
Please come forward if you know anything about this woman...
无论是关于这个女人还是关于塔亚尔
about this incident or about Tayyar Kaymak.
相信我，你提供的信息将能够挽救生命
Believe me, the smallest of information you provide will save a life.
拜托，如果你知道什么，请挺身而出
Please, come forward if you know anything.
不要隐瞒
Don't hide it.
不要隐瞒它，这样女人就不必再隐藏了
Don't hide it, so the woman wouldn't have to hide anymore.
这本书讲了一切
The book has it all.
如何分类文件
How to sort documentation.
有很多方法
There are many ways.
其中之一是
One of them is...
通过给每个字母编号
by numbering each letter.
例如，A代表1，B代表2，C代表3，依此类推。
For example 1 for A, 2 for B, 3 for C and so on.
接着……
And then...
是的，我总是以这种方式对文件进行排序
yes, I always sort my documents this way.
我从未忘记
I never forgot.
当你看到数字
When you see the number...
1682.
费扎夫人，1682
Mrs Feza, 1682.
1是A
1 is A.
不，上面写着“ 1682是8号公寓的密码组合”
No, it said "1682 is the combination for the Flat No:8".
如果有8号公寓，则1682是指其他事情
If there is No:8, 1682 refers to something else.
所以不是1，而是16
So, it is not 1, It is 16.
如果是16
If it's 16...
A，B，C，?，D，E
A, B, C, ?, D, E...
M
M.
梅布鲁雷
Mebrule.
你可以随时拨打此电话
You can call me on this number anytime.
我只想找到那个女人
All I want is to find that woman.
如果有人对我这样做，破坏我的尊严……
If someone did that to me, ruining my dignity...
我会自杀
I would commit suicide.
你说什么？
What did you say?
是的，就是你
Yes, you.
我什么都没说
I said nothing.
是的，你说如果这件事发生在你身上……
Yes, you did. You said if it happened to you...
我说过要自杀 不是吗？
I said I would commit suicide. Wouldn't you?
一个男人强奸了你，你会继续生活吗？
A man rapes you and you carry on living?
谁能承受？
Who can bear it?
你怎么能面对亲人？
How can you face your loved ones?
你怎么能回家告诉你的亲人呢？
How can you go back home, to your family?
梅布鲁雷区
Mebrule Blocks.
我知道了费扎夫人
I've got it Mrs Feza. Mebrule Blocks.
8号公寓 但是最后的“ 2”是什么？
Flat no: 8. But what is the "2" at the end?
梅布鲁雷区 8号公寓
Mebrule Blocks, flat no: 8.
16、8、2，B
16, 8, 2, B.
贝约鲁
Beyo?lu.
阿加·贝尤鲁
Agah, Beyo?lu.
梅布鲁雷区，第8单元公寓，贝尤鲁大楼 我知道了
Mebrule Blocks, flat 8, Beyo?lu. I've got it.
费扎夫人，我找到了房子
Mrs Feza, I found the house.
我找到地址 起来吧
I found the address. Get up.
起来，我们要回家了
Get up, we are going home.
费扎太太，我知道了
Mrs Feza, I've got it. Come on.
我们回局里查档案
Let's go back to the station. We'll check the archives.
寻找什么？
To look for what?
最近15年的自杀事件
Suicides committed in the last 15 years...
如果需要的话，我们回溯20??年
and we'll go back 20 years if necessary.
因为那个女孩自杀了
Because the girl committed suicide.
塔亚尔强奸的那个女孩自杀了
The girl whom Tayyar raped committed suicide.
这就是为什么我们找不到她
That's why we can't find her.
因为她已经死了
Because she is no longer alive.
我们有地址的 我怎么就不记得了？
We've got the address. How could I not remember it?
请等一下，让我将书本放回原处
Just a minute, let me put the book back in its place.
好了
Yes.
费扎夫人
Mrs Feza.
弗拉明戈？
Flamenco?
-奥莱-当然，奥莱
- Olé. - Sure, Olé.
好吧好吧
Well, well, well...
尊敬的检察官先生，我可以看到你玩的很愉快
the honourable D.A, I can see you're having a good time.
很抱歉打扰，但我们不得不谈谈
I am sorry to interrupt but we have to talk.
你怎么知道我在这里？
How did you know I was here?
我怎么知道？
How did I know?
我的团队里有很多线人
I have as many informants as officers in my team.
他们告诉我一切
They tell me everything.
你去哪里，什么时候完成工作
Where you go, what time you finish work.
他们告诉我一切
They tell me everything.
你想要什么？
What do you want?
现在，尊敬的检察官
Now, the honourable D.A...
是谁一直在纠缠我的案子，为什么？
who has been messing with my case and why?
这是第一个问题
This is number one.
还有第二个……
And the number two...
是谁特别指定菲鲁兹
who specifically reinstated the man to the case...
恢复到案件调查中
whom I removed.
谁在插手此案？怎么回事？
Who is running this case? What's going on?
听着，我给你一些建议
Look, a little advice from me...
你知道升官的秘诀吗？
do you know the secret to move up in the ladder?
不问问题
Not to ask questions.
去尼玛的升官
F... ck the ladder.
我一点都不想往上爬 行不行？
I don't want to move up anywhere. How about that?
不往上爬意味着你会被困在原地
Not moving up means you are stuck where you are.
那就是你被埋葬的地方
And that's where you'll be buried.
你在威胁我吗
Are you threatening me?
不，只是谈论管理的简单规则
No, just talking about a simple rule of management.
我喜欢这样的管理规则
Rule of management. I like that.
有那么一瞬间，我以为你在威胁我
For a moment, I thought you were threatening me.
因为我对威胁过敏所以很痒
Because I am allergic to it. It gives me the itch.
当有人威胁我时 我会威胁回去
When someone threatens me I threaten them back.
现在，说到威胁……
Now, talking about threats...
你美丽而受人尊敬的妻子知道你在这里做什么吗？
does your beautiful and respected wife know what you are up to here?
你是是个好人 托尔加 你不会做这样的事情
You are a good man Tolga. You wouldn't do such a thing.
你内心没有邪恶
You haven't got the evil in you.
是的，我没有邪恶
That's right. I haven't got the evil.
但是当我走出去那扇门 什么都有可能会发生
But when I walk out that door anything can happen.
你永远不知道人有多大能耐
You never know what a man is capable of doing.
人类是不可预测的物种
Mankind is an unpredictable species.
我不知道是谁的命令
I don't know who gave the orders.
他们分别联系了内政部和司法部
They called both from Ministry of Internal Affairs and Ministry of Justice.
他们告诉我该怎么做，我只是执行
They told me what to do and I agreed.
我发誓，我不知道是谁在发号施令
I swear, I don't know who is pulling the strings.
你不会对别人说什么，对吗？
You won't say anything to anyone, will you?
每个人都有弱点
Everybody has a soft belly.
能否被诱惑吸引取决于一个人的人格
Being lured by temptations depends on the one's personality.
那是你的问题 与我无关
And that's your problem. It has nothing to do with me.
玩得开心
Have fun.
你跳得太好了 费扎夫人 真的太好了
You are great Mrs Feza. You really are.
你很棒
You were great.
来吧，不要让孩子们等着
Come on, let's not keep the children waiting.
我们现在可以走了吗？
Shall we go now?
好 再跳一首曲子
O.K, one more.
这是最后一个
This is the last one.
等一下 让我们好好跳
Just a minute. Let's do it properly.
女士们先生们……
Ladies and gentlemen...
弗拉门戈舞蹈史上最伟大的舞者
greatest name of all times of flamenco dance.
一位特殊的天才……
A unique talent...
塞诺拉·费萨
Senora Feza.
[死亡原因：自杀]
[Cause of Death: Suicide.
费扎夫人？
Mrs Feza?
发生了什么？？
What happened?
怎么了？你还好吗？
What happened? Are you alright?
你能听到我吗？
Can you hear me?
费扎夫人？
Mrs Feza?
拜托不要这样
Please, don't do this.
这不可能
This can't be happening.
不要啊
Please.
你能听到我费扎夫人吗？
Can you hear me Mrs Feza?
拜托，不要这样
Please, don't. Don't do this.
请不要
Please, no.
我本打算要带你回家
I was going to take you home.
我本打算要为你做饭
I was going to cook for you.
我本打算要为你编织一件毛衣
I was going to knit a jumper for you.
我本打算要照顾你的
I was going to look after you.
我无法照顾梅布鲁雷，但是我要照顾你
I was unable to look after Mebrule. But I was going to look after you.
我不会像穆罕默德先生那样 我永远不会抱怨
I wasn't going to be like Mr Mehmet. I was never going to moan.
我本打算要照顾你的
I was going to look after you.
我把一切都计划好了
I thought of everything.
我本打算把你介绍给我的女儿
I was going to introduce you to my daughter.
我本打算把你介绍给我的孙子
I was going to introduce you to my grandchild.
我要说：“看，这是费扎太太”
I was going to say "Look, this is Mrs Feza."
“她是我的亲爱的老朋友”
"She is a dear old friend of mine".
“她不舒服”“她住在疗养院”
"She is not well". "She is staying in a nursing home".
“但是她在那里感到孤独和不快乐”“从现在开始，她将和我们住在一起”
"But she is lonely and unhappy there". "From now on, she'll be staying with us."
“她将永远和我们在一起”
"She'll be forever staying with us".
拜托不要这样
Please, don't do this.
这不可能
This can't be happening.
奥莱！奥莱！奥莱！
Olé, Olé, Olé.
[嗨，德瓦，我是“狗杀手”]
[Hi Deva, I am the "Dog Killer".
[滚开！]
[F... ck off!
[你不相信我] [但是这个小礼物可能会说服你]
[You don't believe me.] [But this little gift may convince you.]
-你要出去吗？-我马上回来
- Are you going out? - I'll be right back.
内芙拉！
Nevra!
等等！
Wait!
内芙拉！
Nevra!
你还好吗？
Are you alright?
雷汉
Reyhan.
什么？
What?
雷汉自杀了
Reyhan committed suicide.
谁是雷汉？
Who is Reyhan?
不要告诉任何人，好吗？
Don't tell anybody, O.K?
你向我保证 内芙拉 不要忘记
You promised Nevra. Don't forget.
好，我不会忘记
O.K, I won't forget.